Scott Harvey

Senior Software Developer | ColdFusion Specialist (202) 744-5379 | scott.harvey@outlook.com | https://portfolio.scottharvey.dev

SUMMARY

Software developer with over fifteen years of experience building, maintaining, and enhancing applications that improve and automate business processes for organizations including the U.S. Air Force, Environmental Protection Agency, National Institutes of Health, and the Association of American Medical Colleges. I strive to enhance usability and efficiency while maintaining coding and development standards.

- Adobe Certified Expert in ColdFusion
- Eligible for Security Clearance

SKILLS

Language: ColdFusion | JavaScript: React (Next), JSX, Node (Express), JQuery | PHP

HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | XML

Database: MS SQL Server | Oracle | MongoDB | MySQL

Tools: IDEs: Brackets | Dreamweaver | Visual Studio Code

DevOps: GitHub | Subversion | TortoiseSVN | Bamboo

Prototyping and Design: Balsamiq | Photoshop | Illustrator | InDesign | Fireworks

Troubleshooting: Splunk

Management: Jira | Slack | HubSpot CMS

EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE WORK

Noble Technologies, Inc.

Freelance Database Developer

August 2019 — present

Performing routine data management tasks, including database backups, data loads, data validation, and report writing. Assisting with database design and modeling, stored procedure writing, and interface support.

MS SQL Server

AgencyQ

Freelance Web Developer

Feb 2019 — present

Working with content and marketing team as a HubSpot CMS developer to create new, responsive modules for websites. Staging new modules for approval prior to moving modules to production. New modules include featured blog posts, client testimonials, and an image rotator retrieving data from HubDB database queries.

HubSpot CMS

Freelance Web Developer

November 2006 — 2013

Developing and maintaining software for clients of the company.

ColdFusion | Oracle | HTML | JavaScript

- National Institutes of Health (NIH), 2009 2013: Maintaining and developing new functionality for the National Institute on Drug Abuse division's report-creation tool Jennica.
- Best Cellars, 2007: Completing an e-commerce migration.

Scott Harvey | Senior Software Developer | Washington, DC

FULL-TIME WORK

American Association of Medical Colleges (AAMC)

June 2016 — September 2018

Senior Software Engineer

Developing and maintaining survey and reporting tools serving association members, including medical schools, students, and faculty.

ColdFusion | Oracle | HTML | JavaScript | CSS

- Providing software design, coding, testing, implementation, documentation, and maintenance on a team of 2 developers, a business analyst, a quality assurance specialist, and a project manager.
- Performing data analysis, research, and ad hoc reporting according to client needs.
- Projects included:
 - o Development Survey Reporting on fundraising efforts for member institutions.
 - Faculty Salary Survey Reporting on faculty salaries for member institutions.
 - o GME Track Reporting on post-graduate education for medical school graduates.
 - Student Record System Tracking students from matriculation to graduation for AAMC.

Solution Technology Systems, Inc. (STSI)

January 2015 — June 2016

Senior Software Developer

Developing and maintaining Personal Security System, an automated workflow application that initiates, tracks, and manages background investigations for all Environmental Protection Agency personnel.

ColdFusion | Oracle | HTML | JavaScript | CSS

- Providing software design, information architecture, coding, testing, implementation, documentation, and maintenance on a team of 3 developers, 6 analysts, and a project manager.
- Analyzing, coding, testing, and deploying 40+ change requests to production code, using CMMI processes.
- Identifying business and technical solutions to enable the EPA to optimize business performance.

Council for Logistics Research (CLR)

November 2003 — December 2014

Senior Web Developer

Developing and maintaining software for CLR and its clients including the US Air Force.

ColdFusion | MS SQL Server | HTML | JavaScript | CSS

- Developing The Eye, a robust browser-based enterprise resource planning (ERP) application that automates CLR's business and personnel processes, including:
 - o Translating business needs into functional requirements and specifications.
 - Automating processes that were previously done with pen and paper including expense reports, purchase orders, purchase requisitions, performance reviews, training requests, time entry and attendance, while adhering to DCAA regulations.
 - o Consolidating multiple data sources into a single, secure repository for streamlined reporting.
- Designing, developing, and implementing software applications for the U.S. Air Force and other CLR clients.
 - o Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) software
 - Event registration and evaluation software
 - o Content management software, including role-based security, maintenance, and search
 - o Custom web-based surveys with functionality for branching, download, and analysis
 - Resume and skill set tracking system

Scott Harvey

Senior Software Developer | ColdFusion Specialist (202) 744-5379 | scott.harvey@outlook.com | https://portfolio.scottharvey.dev

- Supporting internal staff with technical solutions to increase efficiency and achieve business goals such as adding functionality for versioning, editing, and review to the website content management tool.
- Implementing coding standards for 2-person software development team.
- Managing and mentoring junior developer with software best practices and emerging technologies.

Capital Markets Technology Inc.

2002 - 2003

Web Application Developer

Migrating portions of a client-server intranet from Visual Basic to the browser.

ColdFusion | MS SQL Server | HTML | JavaScript

Q Industries 1999 — 2002

Web Developer

EDUCATION, TRAINING, AND CERTIFICATIONS

- Full Stack Web Developer Certificate, Hyperion Dev, March-September 2019
- Certified Expert in ColdFusion, Adobe, 2010
- Fast Track to ColdFusion 2000 and Advanced ColdFusion 8 Development, Fig Leaf Software, 2008
- Intro to Graphic Design, Corcoran College of Art and Design, 2007
- Hands-On IT Project Management, Project Management Institute, 2005
- Carnegie Mellon University, Mellon College of Sciences, 1992 1995